# Fab Tabs Shop Notes — Blog Setup Guide
### blog.primochops.com, hosted free on Cloudflare Pages, published via GitHub

## What you're getting

8 files, ready to go live:
- `index.html` — the post list / homepage
- `posts/3-bolt-vs-single-bolt-exhaust-flange.html` — one real, finished post to start with
- `style.css` — the shared design (shop-tag cards over your psychedelic swirl background)
- `swirl-lines.svg` — the tiled linework pattern used in the background
- `rss.xml` — feed so people (and Google) can subscribe/track updates
- `sitemap.xml` + `robots.txt` — so search engines crawl it properly

No build tools, no framework, no `npm install`. Every page is a plain HTML file. Publishing a new post is: write the file, add two lines to two other files, push.

---

## Step 1 — Put it on GitHub

1. Go to [github.com](https://github.com) and create a free account if you don't have one
2. Click **New repository**. Name it something like `fabtabs-blog`. Keep it **Public** (needed for the free Cloudflare Pages tier). Don't initialize with a README — you're uploading files directly.
3. On the new empty repo's page, click **uploading an existing file**
4. Drag in all 7 files/folders from the download (keep the `posts/` folder structure intact)
5. Commit directly to the `main` branch

That's it — your blog now exists in a GitHub repo, nothing live yet.

---

## Step 2 — Connect it to Cloudflare Pages

You already have a Cloudflare account from the DNS migration, so this reuses it.

1. Log into [dash.cloudflare.com](https://dash.cloudflare.com)
2. In the left sidebar, find **Workers & Pages** → **Create** → **Pages** → **Connect to Git**
3. Authorize Cloudflare to access your GitHub account, then select the `fabtabs-blog` repo
4. Build settings: leave **Framework preset** as "None," leave the **Build command** blank, set **Build output directory** to `/` (just a single slash — this is a plain static site, nothing to build)
5. Click **Save and Deploy**

Cloudflare will give you a working URL like `fabtabs-blog.pages.dev` within a minute or two. Open it and confirm the blog loads correctly before moving on.

---

## Step 3 — Point blog.primochops.com at it

1. Still in Cloudflare, go to your Pages project → **Custom domains** → **Set up a custom domain**
2. Enter `blog.primochops.com` → **Continue** → **Activate domain**

Because your DNS is already on Cloudflare, it will typically add the required CNAME record automatically. If it doesn't:
1. Go to **DNS** for the `primochops.com` zone
2. Add a record: Type **CNAME**, Name `blog`, Target `fabtabs-blog.pages.dev`, Proxy status **Proxied** (orange cloud)

Give it a few minutes, then visit `https://blog.primochops.com` — it should load your blog with a valid SSL certificate, same as the rest of your Cloudflare-managed domain.

---

## Step 4 — Publish your next post (the actual workflow going forward)

Every time you write a new post, you're touching **3 files**:

### 1. Create the post file
Copy `posts/3-bolt-vs-single-bolt-exhaust-flange.html`, rename it to match your new post (e.g. `posts/heavy-metal-vs-mild-steel.html`), and edit:
- The `<title>` and `<meta name="description">` tags at the top
- The category stamp, date, and heading inside `<article>`
- The body content

### 2. Add it to `index.html`
Copy the `<li class="tag-card">...</li>` block, paste it **above** the "NEW POST TEMPLATE" comment (newest post goes first), and edit the link, stamp, date, title, and excerpt.

### 3. Add it to `rss.xml` and `sitemap.xml`
Same idea — copy the template block in each file, fill in your new post's details, paste above the comment.

Then push the changed files back to GitHub (drag-and-drop the updated files into the repo again, or use GitHub Desktop if you want a proper local workflow later). **Cloudflare Pages redeploys automatically within about a minute of any push** — no redeploy button to remember.

---

## A note on the design

The background is an original tiled swirl pattern in your site's palette — pink, teal, gold, and periwinkle blue, with hand-drawn-style black linework, matching the psychedelic look on primochops.com itself (built from scratch, not copied from any stock image, so there's no licensing risk). Since that pattern is busy, the header, each post preview, and the full article body all sit on solid cream panels — styled like shop tags and work tickets — so text stays easy to read against it. Headlines use a bold condensed face (Oswald) like stamped signage; dates, categories, and links use a monospace face (JetBrains Mono) like a part number stencil.

---

## What this doesn't do (yet)

- **No tag/category archive pages.** At low volume (a post every few weeks), the single homepage list covers it. If you get past ~15-20 posts, say the word and I'll build category pages.
- **No comments.** Intentional — keeps this zero-maintenance. If you want reader engagement, Instagram is still the better venue for that.
- **No search.** Same reasoning — not worth the complexity until there's a real archive to search through.

---

## Quick sanity checklist once it's live

1. `https://blog.primochops.com` loads and looks right on both desktop and phone
2. `https://blog.primochops.com/posts/3-bolt-vs-single-bolt-exhaust-flange.html` loads directly
3. `https://blog.primochops.com/rss.xml` shows valid XML in the browser
4. Submit `https://blog.primochops.com/sitemap.xml` to Google Search Console **as a new, separate property** from primochops.com (subdomains are treated as distinct in Search Console)
5. Add a link to the blog somewhere on primochops.com itself (a nav link or footer link) — this is what actually passes SEO benefit between the two, since a subdomain doesn't automatically share authority with the main domain
